{
  "reference_number": "3007",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "No reason for one. The Arctic Oscillation it turning cool (eg Atlantic Cod back in British waters. The Pacific Oscillation has been cool for ten years, the Antarctic for longer. Last cool arctic, some of\n\n th0se now crying hot, were fearing an Ice Age. Each c.63yr full cycle, we get this alarmism along the way.)"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Real mixed forestry on land above \"Moderately Steep\" rating is a good idea, but with better managment and local end-use. We can make wood like steel now...."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "No govt may bind any future one, in a democracy."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Ditto above (7)"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We need to consider that the Models used are totally useless as admitted in AR4 and before. They are only predicated on a CO2 knob, and cannot handle clouds or water vapour, nor\n convection etc on the fine or medium scales. The computing power needed is close enough to infinite. The Russian ones are least wrong, because they incorporate solar cycles. AR5 is just\n\n waffling, using non-scientific 'scenarios' etc as if they had meaning."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Skilled Experimental physisicsts are needed, to show what gases are and are not capable of, and how radiation operates. Also how it is not heat."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Zero carbon is death. Carbon chemistry is Organic Chemistry, the chemistry of Life. Life has been happier at about ten times the current levels....."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Climate changes, or it would not be named. Untill the next glaciation, sea levels will rise, so sensible building rules are a good idea. 200m setback from seas for instance. Mitigation as needed\n by sound engineering and agricultural practice."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We have been studying this subject for years ( I have a Degree and Grad Dip (Massey 2006) and 70yrs of experience. We recently identified the onset of the current 'Quiet Sun' period and\n\nanticipate the current cooling phase to last at least 20yrs more. In the cycle (mainly from oceanic solar input) of c63yrs, we are at a similar stage to the early 1960s which I remember well. It is\nnot hotter now. We also know why Maurice Strong started this CAGW thing. It is political, not scientific. \"On page 982 from WD1AR5 final they don​t call it a plateau, but it is what it is.\" ​The ASK\n\nresults and the initialised predictions both suggest that those CMIP5 models that warm most rapidly over the period (1986​2005) to (2016​2035) may be inconsistent with the observations.​\n\nhttp://www.coyoteblog.com/coyote_blog/2007/04/look_at_the_pol.html https://www.google.co.nz/search?\nq=air+pollution&hl=en&prmd=imvnsb&source=lnms&tbm=isch&ei=thGsT47PGqPq2AWHitymAg&sa=X&oi=mode_link&ct=mode&cd=2&ved=0CDAQ_AUoAQ&biw=1393&bih=999&gws_rd=cr\n\nhttps://www.iceagenow.info/ontarios-new-premier-must-save-the-province/ https://enthusiasmscepticismscience.wordpress.com/2012/08/07/madrid-1995-the-last-day-of-climate-science/\n\nhttps://enthusiasmscepticismscience.wordpress.com/2012/04/21/madrid-1995-was-this-the-tipping-point-in-the-corruption-of-climate-science/ https://duckduckgo.com/?\nq=ben+santer+alters+spm+1995&t=ffsb&ia=web http://www.drroyspencer.com/2017/05/santer-takes-on-pruitt-the-global-warming-pause-and-the-devolution-of-climate-science/"
    }
  ]
}
